A-Z guarantee claims are an important component
of Amazon's commitment to customer satisfaction
and seller accountability.
These claims cover both the timely delivery
and condition of items upon receipt
and provide buyers with a way to seek resolution
for order issues, regardless of whether the order
was fulfilled by Amazon or directly by you.
Before becoming eligible to file a claim,
buyers must first contact you directly
through buyer seller messages,
unless an instant customer refund applies.
For delivery related issues, such as late delivery
or an item not showing up, buyers must wait 48 hours
for a response from you.
If you do not respond within the 48 hour period,
the buyer can then become eligible
to file an A-Z guarantee claim.
Buyers must also wait at least three calendar days
past the maximum estimated delivery date EDD
before filing a claim.
For order return issues, such as an item showing up damaged
or not as described, buyers must first submit
a return request to you.
If you do not authorize the return
or provide a prepaid return label
with a valid domestic or international return address
and valid tracking within 48 hours,
the buyer can file an A-Z guarantee claim.
This formal process allows Amazon to review the situation
and determine a fair outcome.
You'll receive email notification
when a customer files a claim.
You can also track and take action on claims
filed by customers by navigating to the performance menu tab
in your seller central account
and selecting the A-Z guarantee claims page.
All claims that require a response from you
will be under the action required tab.
Find the relevant claim and select respond to Amazon.
Enter your comments in the text box
and include any information that may help us
better understand the claim and your position
on whether it should be granted.
Use buyer seller messages
if you want to attach additional information.
Then click submit.
If you are searching for a particular claim,
enter the corresponding ASIN or order ID
to view related claims.
All claims that are under investigation
and claim decisions that have not been concluded
will be listed in the under review tab.
Claims where a decision has been made in favor of the buyer
and you have an option to appeal
will appear under the option to appeal tab.
You can appeal within 30 calendar days
of Amazon's decision.
Find the relevant claim and select appeal decision.
In the comments field,
provide a brief description of the situation,
including details about your order,
your communication with the buyer, delivery,
or signature confirmation details,
tracking information, refund information,
or anything else to support your side of the claim.
Then click submit.
Once an A-Z guarantee claim is filed,
there are four possible outcomes.
First, you can choose to issue a full refund
by clicking refund customer
as the investigation is under progress
and the claim will be closed.
If you issue a refund to the customer,
you may choose to request
that the customer return the item
before you process the refund.
Second, Amazon can investigate the claim
and determine whether to grant the claim
in favor of the customer.
During this process, Amazon may ask you
for additional information
and to recount your version of events,
which you must respond to within 72 hours
to avoid the claim being automatically granted
in the customer's favor.
Third, the claim can be automatically granted
in certain circumstances,
such as not responding to the customer's
buyer seller message within the 48-hour period,
shipping and delivery failures,
unresolved return requests,
and problems with return shipments or refunds.
Last, the customer can withdraw the claim
and the claim is closed.
Each of these outcomes will impact
your order defect rate, ODR,
which is a key measure of your ability
to provide a good customer experience.
It includes all orders with one or more defects
represented as a percentage of total orders
during a given 60-day period.
To uphold customer expectations,
we require sellers to maintain an ODR under 1%
in order to sell in the Amazon store,
An ODR above 1% may result in account deactivation.
Your ODR will reflect in your account health page
located in the performance menu tab
in your Seller Central account.
The following types of claims can impact your ODR.
Claims that are granted to the buyer
and Amazon determines that you were at fault.
Claims for which you refunded the buyer
after the claim was filed.
Claims for which you or Amazon canceled the order.
Claims that are pending a decision on appeal.
You can learn more about ODR,
as well as how to manage and prevent A to Z guarantee claims
by visiting the Amazon A to Z guarantee claims
help page resources in your Seller Central account.